JENNIFER LINDSEY

Irvine, CA 92618 Email: <u>ilindsey010@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: <u>Jennifer-Lindsey</u> | GitHub: <u>JJLindsey</u> Portfolio: <u>jjlindsey.github.io/react-portfolio/</u>

SUMMARY

FrontEnd Web Developer with a background in Art & Design and a dedication to life-long learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications, I bring strong attention to detail to my work as a developer. Experience in collaborating to create and deliver materials that are accessible to all audiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React.js, CSS, HTML5, jQuery, Bootstrap, Material Design

Back-End: NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, JSON, GraphQL, JWT

Tools: Git, GitHub, NPM, VSCode, Heroku, Chrome Dev Tools

Other: Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator, Agile

Familiar with: CSS animations, RESTful APIs, SPA using React, jQuery, PWA, SQL

PROJECTS

One Stop Print Shop

GitHub | Deployed

- Full stack MERN Application using GraphQL API designed to allow users to sign-up & log-in to an E-Commerce site that uses Stripe API for checkout. By signing up through the app, user can add products to their cart, and if user goes off-line the cart contents will persist..
- Role: Front End components & pages, functionality of creating Global State, shopping cart, Stripe API functionality, CSS, Bootstrap.

State of the Art

GithHub | Deployed

- Full stack Application designed to allow museums and similar institutions to add, search, and edit location of artwork. By signing up through the app, the user can then add title, artist, date, medium, style and location of their institution's artwork.
- Role: UI design, creating log-in functionality, building the dataset, styling w/ CSS & Bootstrap, Handlebars framework.

Brewed Force

GitHub | Deployed

- Website designed to unite the beer minded traveler with new breweries and beers in new cities. By entering a city into the search feature, the user will be met with a list of breweries in that city. We used the Open Brewery API & Punk API.
- Role: UI design, CSS, Material Design Lite, JavaScript for local storage.
- JavaScript/HTML/CSS/Material Design Lite

EXPERIENCE

Museum Educator | Kimbell Art Museum | 2019 – June 2020

Work collaboratively with fellow museum educators to create and present interactive gallery & studio art programs using the elements & principles of art. Modeled critical thinking to connect audiences to works of art within the permanent collection. Researched artworks within collection to keep lessons within cultural & historical context.

Teaching hatha yoga, mindful flow, yoga nidra and meditation classes in corporate and private sessions. Providing a safe & supportive environment for all levels of practitioners

Art History Professor | Southern New Hampshire University | 2013 - 2015

Taught Modern Art, Art History and Art Appreciation courses in an online environment, engaging students through discussion board and article reflections, & journals.

Visual Thinking Strategies Internship | Boston MFA | 2012

Observed teachers in the classroom to facilitate discussions of visual art to increase student engagement, performance, and enjoyment of learning. Scored, transcribed essays for database for research of teaching critical thinking skills in a classroom setting.

Coordinator | Hope Cottage | 2010 - 2011

Designed a state-wide marketing campaign for non-profit, mobile media ad. Created & implemented Client Management Database for reporting. Developed, wrote, and edited database manual for staff.

EDUCATION

Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN

2021

Bootcamp Certificate: remote 24-week intensive MERN program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJS, JSON, MySQL, SQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, GraphQL, & ReactJS. Experience in pair-programming, and agile method working remotely with peers.

Courtauld Institute of Art, University of London, London, England **MA – Art History**

University of Texas, Arlington, TX

BA - Art History and French, Summa Cum Laude

Additional Skills

Critical thinking and analysis
Presentations and public speaking
Excellent communication skills
Strong writing skills
Competent in adapting content for diverse audiences
Research
Problem-solving and decision-making
Attention to detail
Organization & Time management
Ability to work autonomously or with a team
Aesthetic and design conscious for UI & UX
Creativity
Adaptable & excited to learn new technologies